





## **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Client Relationship Management, Marketing Engineer, Sales Order Processing, ISO Audit, Technical Sales, Payment Followup, MS Office, Customer Service, Project Planning, Project Execution, Project Control, Project Monitoring, Installation, Commissioning

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

# Summary

B.E (Electronics and Communication) with more than 6 Years of experience in Planning & Operation, Sales & Marketing, Sales & Operation and CRM

C urrently associated with Satco Lighting Pvt. Ltd. as Marketing Engineer.

A Sales & Marketing professional with proven record of success in securing several profitable businesses by holding techno-commercial negotiations with clients

Experience in charting out sales strategies and contributing towards enhancing business volumes & growth and achieving revenue and profitability norms.

Competent in implementing effective solutions to the customer needs, with an aim to improve customer contentment and consequently customer loyalty, repeat and referral business.

Acquires and applies professional/technical knowledge, skills, experience, and judgment to accomplish results, serve customers better and contribute to the organization's intellectual capital.

### **Work Experience**

SATCO LIGHTING PVT. LTD as Marketing Engineer

Jun 2019 to Till Date

Company Profile:

The Company mainly deals in energy efficient lighting and to provide the complete solution of lighting to the Retail showroom, Jewelry showroom, Mobile showroom, commercial building etc.

Understand the client requirement over phone visit them on confirmation.

Prepare the quotation, send the technical specification to client for specified/ selected product.

Lead generation by using the old database as well as developing new client.

Generate the revenue from the new client. Direct Sales of the lighting products to retail clients.

Visit the client of supplied/installed lights about the performance of the light.

Prepare daily, weekly and monthly report. Cold Calling for meeting.

GANDHI AUTOMATION PVT. LTD as Sr. Executive Planning & Operation Jan 2015 to Nov 2018

Company Profile:

The Company mainly deals in Industrial overhead door, Fire rated sliding door, Fire rated shutter, Motorized sliding door, Motorized swing door, Hanger Door, Dock Leveler &Dock shelter used in industries as well as at the warehouse.

Responsibilities:

Discussion with project co-coordinators on all sites.

Co-ordination with team members towards assigning the various tasks to ensure the successful installation at client sites

Preparing installation certificates/documents for the products.

Handling the situations in case of miss communication by executive, customer care or sinners of given the proper solutions to client.

Co-ordinate with the site engineers on daily basis for continue running project.

Do the proper documentation after successful completion of project.

#### Artech Instruments and Controls Pvt. Ltd as Sales Engineer

Mar 2012 to Dec 2014

Company Profile:

The Company mainly deals in Temperature, Humidity and Gas instruments widely used in Steel & Non-Ferrous Metal manufacturing plants, Oxygen/Nitrogen Gas plants, Boiler/Furnace Applications, Energy audit companies, Cold Storages, Pharmaceutical companies, etc.

Responsibilities:

Preparing Quotation, follow-up with same

Payment follow up.

Looking after the sales of the company, plan monthly sales targets and reselling of non-standard products.

Contacting and maintaining follow ups of customers using CRM

Take part in ISO audit.

Maintaining the Sales & Service record of site.

Understanding customer's requirements and suggesting suitable products according to the requirements.

Visiting steel plants and Gas Plants for installations of the instruments.

Take part for drafting Instrument manuals

^ Back to Top

#### Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Hectronics/Telecommunication) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2011

PG: only BE (electronics and communication) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Master in Global digital marketing

C & C++

Data scientist complete bootcamp

^ Back to Top

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
WINDOWS	10	2018	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
C, C++, HTML, VLSI, Mat lab and VHDL			
PowerPoint, Word and Excel	Office 201	2018	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Visual Basic- 6 and 8051			

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Gujarati	Expert	✓	✓	✓
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Marathi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Kannada	Proficient			✓

^ Back to Top

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General US Work Status: Need H1 Visa Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.